Simon Fraser University publications collection
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Simon Fraser University publications collection
1964 - 1999
F-219
Q106664363
12 cm of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Original newspaper clippings have been photocopied due to their fragile condition.
Archives and Records Management Department
The University Archives acquires, preserves and makes available three categories of materials: (1) the official records of the University, including those created by the Board of Governors, Senate, University committees, faculties, departments and administrative offices; (2) materials documenting the wider University community; and (3) historical research collections that promote the teaching and research activities of the University.
The Archives was established within the University Library in 1968 when librarian Liisa Fagerlund was appointed University Archivist on a half-time basis. She continued in this post until 1975 when she left the University. From 1975 to 1978, the Archives functioned within the Special Collections division of the Library. Archival duties were carried out by various library staff members. In 1978, the University Archives was established as a separate administrative unit outside of the Library. Donald Baird, recently retired as University Librarian, became University Archivist and held this position until his retirement in 1990. Jim Ross served as University Archivist from 1991 to 1993, and was succeeded by Ian Forsyth in 1994.
When the Archives was a function of the University Library, the University Archivist reported to the University Librarian. When the Archives was established as a separate administrative unit, the University Archivist reported directly to the University President. The reporting structure changed in 1986 when the University Archivist reported to the Vice-President, Research/Information Systems; in 1990, when the University Archivist reported to the Associate Vice-President, Academic; and in 1996, when the University Archivist reported to the Registrar/Dean of Students.
published
Full
Revised
The title is based on the contents of the collection.
Collection consists of newspaper clippings and periodicals about Simon Fraser University.
The collection has been arranged into two series by the archivist: one for newspaper articles, the other for periodicals.
Textual records
The SFU Archives publications about SFU collection is an artificial collection compiled by Archives staff.
All accessions have been processed as of June 2015. Further accruals are expected.
A second copy of "The Business and Financial Chronicle" (Dec 1965) was donated to the SFU Archives by Diane Stiglish in June 2015.
For other press clippings and periodicals about SFU, see Media and PR fonds (F-61), Ceremonies and Events Office fonds (F-91), Patrick McTaggart-Cowan fonds (F-65), and Office of the President fonds (F-193).
The files are open with no restrictions.
File and item lists are available.
- Newspaper articles, 1965 - 1999; F-219-1; 6 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of photocopies of newspaper articles relating to Simon Fraser University.
  Files are arranged chronologically.
  Textual records
  All files are open with no access restrictions.
  - Newspaper articles, vol. 1, 1965; F-219-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - small 219-1)
    Open
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-0-0-0-1.
  - Newspaper articles, vol. 2, 1965; F-219-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - small 219-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-0-0-0-2.
  - Newspaper articles, 1966; F-219-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - small 219-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-0-0-0-3.
  - Newspaper articles, 1967; F-219-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - small 219-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-0-0-0-4.
  - Newspaper articles, 1968; F-219-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - small 219-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-0-0-0-5.
  - Newspaper articles, 1969; F-219-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - small 219-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-0-0-0-6.
  - Newspaper articles, 1970 - 1979; F-219-1-0-0-7 (Archival box - small 219-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-0-0-0-7.
  - Newspaper articles, 1980 - 1989; F-219-1-0-0-8 (Archival box - small 219-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-0-0-0-8.
  - Newspaper articles, 1990 - 1999; F-219-1-0-0-9 (Archival box - small 219-1)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-0-0-0-9.
- Magazine articles, 1964 - 1990; F-219-2; 6 cm of textual records
  Series consists of magazines that contain articles relating to Simon Fraser University.
  - Saturday Night, 1964; F-219-2-0-0-1 (Newspaper box 219-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-item3.
  - Architectural Forum, 1965; F-219-2-0-0-2 (Newspaper box 219-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-item6.
  - Vancouver Life, 1965; F-219-2-0-0-3 (Newspaper box 219-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-item7, F-219-item8.
  - The Business and Financial Chronicle, 1965; F-219-2-0-0-4 (Newspaper box 219-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-item10.
  - Beautiful Burnaby Magazine, 1965; F-219-2-0-0-5 (Newspaper box 219-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-item15, F-219-item16.
  - The Columbian, 1965; F-219-2-0-0-6 (Newspaper box 219-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-item17, F-219-item18.
  - Simon Fraser Bulletin, 1965; F-219-2-0-0-7 (Newspaper box 219-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-item19, F-219-item20, F-219-item21, F-219-item22.
  - Pipeline, 1966; F-219-2-0-0-8 (Newspaper box 219-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-item4.
  - Time, 1966; F-219-2-0-0-9 (Newspaper box 219-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-item5.
  - Maclean's Magazine, 1966; F-219-2-0-0-10 (Newspaper box 219-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-item11, F-219-item12, F-219-item13, F-219-item14.
  - Southam News Service: Confrontation on the Campus, 1968; F-219-2-0-0-11 (Newspaper box 219-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-item1, F-219-item2.
  - Vancouver Boulevard, 1990; F-219-2-0-0-12 (Newspaper box 219-2)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-219-item9.